Monochrome Inverted
Scarstory
Iron-blooded Chapter
March 25th
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Ưm...
K-Không thấy gì đâu.
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Nói sao nhỉ...
Nếu không muốn để người ta nhìn thấy,
thì váy ấy, suy cho cùng không mấy an toàn ha.
Chính ra, mặc quần spat lại kín đáo hơn
kiểu như tường lửa ấy nhỉ.
C-Chịu~
Vậy thôi, chào cậu tớ đi đây.
Ơ chờ đã nào!
Mãi mới đuổi kịp.
Cậu bước đi nhanh thật đấy.
Araragi-kun.
Araragi
Sao cậu lại biết tên tớ thế?
Lại chả biết thì sao.
Tụi mình học cùng trường còn gì.
Ghép bộ "phụ" với chữ "khả" trong "khả năng",
Antigod
viết tiếp 2 lần chữ "ngoan" trong "bé ngoan",
ra
rara
rồi thêm chữ "cây" trong "cây cối",
ta có họ là Araragi-kun.
gi
Còn tên cậu là Lịch từ "âm lịch", tức Koyomi...
Koyomi
Đúng chứ nhỉ?
Thế là thành... Araragi Koyomi-kun.
Araragi Koyomi
Cậu là... Hanekawa...
Hanekawa Tsubasa.
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Ghê~ Cậu biết tên tớ luôn mà.
Đợt thi cuối học kì 1 năm 2,
trong tất cả các môn, tính cả
môn Sức khỏe & Thể chất lẫn các môn Nghệ thuật...
có một người chỉ sai duy nhất một lỗi,
đó là cậu, Hanekawa Tsubasa.
Ơ khoan?! Không phải chứ!
Sao cậu lại nắm rõ thế?
Có khi nào cậu Araragi-kun đây...
lại bám đuôi tớ sao?
Nói thế nghe cứ như kiểu
tớ bị "hoang tưởng bức hại" ấy nhỉ.
Có sao đâu.
Tớ có đứa bạn ngoài hành tinh nói thế này.
Araragi-kun cũng có bạn cơ á?
Sao lại không thắc mắc cái chỗ "ngoài hành tinh" hả!!
À thì tại...
Araragi-kun ý,
lúc nào cũng có một mình,
nên tớ có ấn tượng là
cậu sống tách biệt với mọi người.
Mà... cậu nói đúng rồi đấy, tớ không có bạn.
Nhưng cậu thì nổi tiếng tới cái mức
mà kẻ cô độc như tớ cũng phải biết tới.
Thôi, đừng mà.
Đùa thế không vui đâu.
Này! Araragi-kun.
Say, Araragi.
Araragi-kun có tin vào ma cà rồng không?
Ma cà rồng... thì sao à?
Gần đây ấy,
có hơi rộ lên một tin đồn thế này,
trong thành phố hiện đang có một con ma cà rồng.
Thế nên người ta kêu là đừng có ra ngoài vào ban đêm.
Mơ hồ quá, không đáng tin chút nào.
Họ bảo ả ta tóc vàng, nhan sắc thì tuyệt trần,
ánh mắt thì băng giá
khiến người ta lạnh sống lưng.
Nhưng chỉ có thế
thì sao khẳng định là ma cà rồng được?
Hoàn toàn có thể là một cô gái
với mái tóc vàng nổi bật.
Cơ mà...
họ còn bảo lúc đèn đường chiếu vào
thì mái tóc cứ như là sáng rực lên,
nhưng lại không thấy bóng đâu cả.
Nhưng cũng đêm hôm cả rồi.
Dù nói là được đèn đường chiếu sáng,
chứ vẫn có thể là nhìn nhầm mà.
Ừm! Tớ cũng cho đây là chỉ là tin đồn nhảm.
Nhưng mà...
Tớ ấy nhé, nếu ma cà rồng mà có thật,
thì cũng muốn gặp một lần.
Kiểu như...
tồn tại một thứ cao cấp hơn loài người ấy,
...thích thật nhỉ.
Cao cấp hơn loài người ư?
Kiểu Thần Thánh ấy à?
Không nhất thiết cứ phải là Thần.
Nếu không thì...
chả gặt hái được gì cả đúng không nào?
Ah, my bad.
You're so easy to chat with.
So easy I feel like I said stuff that doesn't make much sense.
It's weird you've got no friends when you're so fun to talk to.
Why don't you make friends?
If I made friends, I'd become less human.
What?
I don't think I'm following.
Well, uh, how do I put this...
If I had friends, I'd have to care about them.
If they got hurt, I'd be hurt too.
If they were sad, I'd be sad too.
Friends are just another weakness.
That's like an affliction for anyone.
But when your friends have fun, you'll have fun too.
When they're happy, you'll be happy too.
It doesn't necessarily have to be a weakness.
No.
Friends having fun would make me jealous.
Their happiness would just make me envious.
You're petty.
Give me a break.
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
I'll be heading to the library now.
Wanna come along?
Why?
What would I do in a library?
Study, of course.
Of course?
Alas, I'm not so diligent as to study during spring break when I don't even have any homework.
But next semester you'll have to
prepare for university entry exams.
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
University?
I'll be happy if I can even graduate.
I'm already a lost cause.
Do you have a cell phone, Araragi-kun?
Uh, yeah?
Gimme.
Thanks. Here.
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
I added my number and email.
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Too bad! You just made a friend.
What the hell?
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Flashback
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Departures
Platform
Express
Local
Naoetsu North
Naoetsu Central
Naoetsu South
Shinjuku
Ginza
Oizumi-gakuen
New York
Indeed,
you shall help me.
Can you not hear me?
You shall help me, I say.
Are...
Are you okay?
I'll get you an ambulance!
Ambulance?
I need no such thing.
Instead,
offer me your blood.
Do you believe in vampires?
They say it's a hauntingly beautiful blonde woman
with eyes so cold it chills you to the bone.
I am Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade,
the iron-blooded, hot-blooded, and cold-blooded vampire.
I shall take your blood as my flesh.
Therefore, offer me your blood.
Aren't vampires... supposed to be immortal?
I lost too much blood.
Too much to even regenerate or transform.
I am about to die.
As a lowly human, you should consider
becoming my flesh to be a great honor.
B-Blood?
Can't you get a transfusion or something?
H-How much do you need?
Everything you have should keep me alive for now.
I see. All I've got.
What's wrong?
Offer me your blood!
Now! Hurry!
Hurry, you fool!
It's fine.
I can get away.
Can you imagine a greater honor?!
I can get away from this.
Just run.
That will let me
escape this reality.
What?
S-Surely you jest.
You refuse to help me?
No!
No! No! I don't wanna die!
I don't wanna die! I don't wanna die!
Help me! Help me, please!
Please, I beg you!
Help me...
No!
I'm sorry!
I would die.
She's a monster!
She's a vampire!
I don't have to help her.
Right?
I know, goddamn it!
Don't give up, you moron!
A-Are you okay with this?
Of course I'm not.
Damn it.
Why?
How did it come to this?
I swear I'll do better in my next life.
I'll be smart, and everything bad that happens will be everyone else's fault.
I'll be reborn into someone like that.
I'll help you.
Take my blood.
I give it all to you.
Every last drop of it.
Suck me dry.
Thank you.
Was it a dream?
Surprise
The hell?!
H-Hey!
W-Wake up.
Just five more minutes.
Five minutes
W—
Wake up already!
Not feeling it right now.
Feeling it
How long are you gonna sleep?!
Like 4.6 billion years.
4.6 billion years
That's enough to create Earth all over again!
March 28th
It's been two days?
Fool!
Good grief.
How stupid do you have to be
to jump right into the sunlight?
Your average vampire would evaporate in an instant.
Never go outside again while the sun is up.
You are immortal, so you would burn and regenerate,
burn and regenerate, in an endless cycle.
Such is the woe of being an immortal vampire.
Vampire?
Wait, are...
Flashback
I very much am Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade.
Call me Heart-under-blade.
It has been 400 years since I made my last kin.
You are my second.
Seeing your regeneration earlier,
I'd call it a great success.
K-Kin?
Kin
Indeed! Therefore you—
That reminds me. I have yet to get your name.
Not that I need to.
The name you once bore is henceforth meaningless.
Well, servant of mine,
welcome to the world of the night.
Where...
Where are we?
I believe it was called a "cram school."
It went bankrupt and fell abandoned a few years ago.
A suitable place to conceal oneself.
Next question, Kiss-shot.
Hold on!
I told you to call me Heart-under-blade!
That's way too long.
I prefer Kiss-shot. It's short.
Can't I call you that?
Oh well.
If that is what you prefer, so be it.
I've no reason to refuse.
So?
What is your next question?
Um...
I turned into a vampire, right?
Is it not obvious?
Do I need to spell it out for you?
You became my kin, my servant.
Consider it an honor.
Your servant...
Why do you have a child's body now?
Earlier you were more, uh, mature—
Sorry for not being more "mature"!
That's not what I meant.
Mature
And
Your limbs were severed
I took all your blood,
but it was insufficient.
I therefore took a form I could sustain.
Better than perishing, I would say.
Then again, I can only sustain a
minimum amount of immortality,
and most of my vampire powers are unavailable now.
Inconvenient indeed.
Flashback
My limbs are restored, as you can see.
I could at least regenerate the form,
if not the power to fill it.
This should suffice for now.
That said, do not forget that you are my servant.
I may look this way now,
but I am a vampire who has lived for five centuries.
You are but a newborn as a vampire.
Know your place when you address me.
O-Oh.
Make your replies clear.
Do you really understand?
I do...
Then as a sign of your obedience, pat my head.
That should do.
Why did you turn me into a vampire?
I was prepared to die being sucked dry by you.
It is not a matter of why.
All who have their blood drunk by a vampire will,
without exception, turn into vampires.
That is all.
I see...
Well, I suppose things worked out for the best.
There is something I need you to do, after all.
Your blood alone only allows me to regenerate so much.
I am far from my full potential.
Which is why you shall act in my stead.
What do you want from me?
Can I...
Can I return to being human?
I thought so.
I was prepared for that question.
So? Can I?!
You can.
I can guarantee that.
I give you my word if needed.
The names of three people who robbed Kiss-shot of parts of her body.
Those three are vampire-slaying specialists.
They're the ones that slew you, then?
Think before speaking, fool!
They have yet to finish me off.
However, they took my limbs.
I have very little regenerative power left too.
I have no chance of standing against them now.
And so, you shall be the one to face those three and take back my limbs.
Huh?
"You shall," as if it was that simple.
To make you human once again, I must regain my full power.
I must be whole again.
My limbs are absolutely necessary for that.
B-But I can't fight at all.
Won't I just get slain instead?
Fool.
You still think as if you were human.
You are now my kin.
Now that I have fallen this low,
while I am still a top-class vampire, you could still kill me.
So you're a weak vampire?
No!
You're weakened, so I might be stronger than you at this point,
but those three managed to take your limbs when you were whole and at full power.
How could I—
I was at a disadvantage because they came at me at once.
I took them lightly.
What I mean is that as long as you take them on one by one,
they shall stand no chance against you.
Simply put: it is an easy task.
W-What now?
Dismember
Would... Would you at least hear me out?!
I-I'm human!
Do you want to murder a fellow human?!
Mur
der
Spin
You're looking lively.
Did something good happen?
Huh?
Thanks for saving me.
No need for thanks.
You got saved on your own,
Araragi-kun.
Don't be so alarmed.
Your stare's sharp.
You're looking lively.
Did something good happen?
Let's just go home for now, Araragi-kun.
Home?
To that old abandoned cram school.
Huh?
Hold on a second!
H-How do you know about that?
Of course I know.
I'm the one who told her about it.
Failing to do the right thing is the sign of cowardice.
Heart-under-blade looked like she was in trouble,
dragging your body around,
so I let her in on a good spot.
Who are you?
I'm just an old fart who happened to pass by.
Don't worry.
I'm no vampire-slaying specialist.
I practice in a much wider field.
I'll introduce myself properly later.
You're back!
Who is that behind you?
I feel like I've met you before.
That's so mean.
You don't remember me?
So?
How did it go?
This is a problem.
Those three are still working together.
They took you out even at your full power.
It's not like I'd stand any chance against them, right?
Which is why I told you to take them on one by one!
They're together. It's not happening.
You said we could just lay low,
but who knows when they'll find us he—
Don't worry about that.
I drew up a boundary around here while you were asleep.
A boundary?
Like a barrier?
Something like that.
What's up with you, exactly?
Why did you help Kiss-shot and me?
I realize you're not an enemy,
but I doubt you'd be on our side either.
Jeez, you're so cruel.
Listen, I'm here to maintain the balance.
Consider that my job.
I bridge this side and the other.
Introduce yourself.
You said you would.
Spin
Oshino Meme.
Oshino Meme
I'm like a rolling stone.
I'm kind of an authority on monsters and apparitions.
Though unlike those three, I'm not great at the whole slaying thing.
Not great?
Let me rephrase that.
I'm not a fan of it.
Doesn't that make you a specialist then?
Maintaining the balance is my specialty.
I negotiate from neutral ground.
Call me a mediator.
Negotiation?
Bridging this side and the other?
Where is "this side" and what's "the other"?
Are the two sides humans and monsters?
Speech / Voice
In that case, now I
belong to which side?
Monsters?
That's good.
I prefer to call them oddities, though.
Oddity
And she's the oddity slayer.
She's a rare kind of vampire who can drain energy from oddities.
That makes her pretty famous, actually.
I listened to your little chat earlier.
Quite the pinch you're in.
I didn't expect things to take such a difficult turn.
There is nothing difficult about it.
It is extremely simple.
In the eyes of an undying vampire, maybe.
It's quite the trouble for us humans.
Right, Araragi-kun?
Also, Heart-under-blade,
I liked how you agreed to return
your kin Araragi-kun to being human.
Should I mediate for you?
Between us and those three?
Who else?
So you'll save us?
No. But I'll lend you a hand.
The balance feels off as it is right now.
It's like I'm watching bullies get their way.
Of course, since it's my job, I'm not gonna do it for free.
Hm...
How about two million?
Two million?!
Akasegawa
Pay when you can. I won't bother you about it.
That much is the least I must ask to maintain the balance.
B-But...
Shall we hear your exact plan?
Negotiations sound nice, but it is not so easy.
Trying to convince those three is futile.
All I can do is ask nicely.
And sincerely.
If asking doesn't work, more dangerous ideas get involved.
If we can at least communicate, we can play a game.
A game?
First, we gotta split 'em up.
You said dealing with them
one by one shouldn't be an issue.
So let's make it happen.
How do you plan to negotiate with them in the first place, boy?
The details are a trade secret.
I'll level the playing field,
and Araragi-kun can get back your limbs.
If you regain your limbs, you also regain your full power,
which means you can give Araragi-kun back his humanity.
Servant!
I cannot procure human money.
I have no idea how heavy a debt two million is.
Can you shoulder it?
Do not worry.
His skills are real.
I may be weak now, but even I can see that.
I don't have that much saved,
but if I get to pay when I can
and you don't press me about it,
and I don't need collateral or a guarantor,
then I'll shoulder it.
It's a deal!
Thanks for your patronage.
Just kidding.
Voice only
Eye for an eye, tooth for a tooth.
Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade
Voice only
Iron-blooded, hot-blooded, and cold-blooded
Vampire for a vampire.
Red
Unnumbered Scene
Vampire
Voice only
Let us begin then.
Dramaturgy
Voice only
A giant of over 2 meters.
A dual wielder, he held
rippled, huge swords in
both his hands. Such
swords are commonly
referred to as flamberge.
He was a goliath, a man of
massive muscles. He wore
a headband to comb up his
unruly hair. He is the
vampire slayer that took
Kiss-shot's right arm.
(omitted)
It was March 31st,
the last day of March.
A giant of over 2 meters.
A dual wielder, he held
rippled, huge swords in
both his hands. Such
swords are commonly
referred to as flamberge.
He was a goliath, a man of
massive muscles. He wore
a headband to comb up his
unruly hair. He is the
vampire slayer that took
Kiss-shot's right arm.
(omitted)
It was March 31st,
the last day of March.
A kin-slayer vampire
Voice only
This shit's hilarious.
Episode
Voice only
He wore a white cloak and had cunning eyes.
He lifted a gargantuan cross three times his size and more
than three times his weight to his shoulder with one hand.
He wore a white cloak and had cunning eyes.
He lifted a gargantuan cross three times his size and more
than three times his weight to his shoulder with one hand.
He is a vampire hunter. He hunts vampires for the prize on their heads.
That makes him a bounty hunter. And furthermore—
Half vampire
Voice only
So ominous.
Guillotine Cutter
Voice only
He resembled a priest, with hair that would rival the back of a hedgehog.
He might even seem gentle at first impression.
Human
A human who denies the existence of oddities.
A human who erases the existence of oddities.
Araragi-kun!
Voice only
Don't worry about me!
Hanekawa Tsubasa
He's a nice guy, but that's not all.
He's strong.
How could I not worry?!
Voice only
Araragi Koyomi
If I can't see you anymore,
That was the first time
there'd be no point in being human again!
I felt like I finally met Hanekawa for real.
No mistakes. Straight, eye to eye.
Araragi-kun.
Preview
Give up being human.
Scarstory
Hot-blooded Chapter
In theaters nationwide summer 2016
Scarstory
Hot-blooded Chapter
In theaters nationwide summer 2016